For crying out loud...
Why is she telling us to cool our heads here for a while?
Leaving us alone in a place like this
won't be any trouble for us anymore.
Being forbidden to use alchemy—
it's like when we were training here that one time, huh?
Do you think that maybe Sensei doesn't feel like we've made any progress at all?
That couldn't be it.
Just a minute! Al! Ed!
Don't get so upset.
You'll fall in.
Okay...
Why are you doing this?
That is a good question.
Yeah.
Don't just "yeah" me!
I don't understand the reason why you're leaving the two of them
on an uninhabited island
all of a sudden!
It's a good question.
Yeah.
Jeez! What in the world
are you thinking?!
This is good to do
every now and then.
It's nice to stop and think things over once in a while.
It's something those two need to do right now.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Al...
Should we run away?
We can't!
After all, I can't swim!
Come to think of it,
neither can I.
That's right. We're not
the same as we used to be.
Not us.
This is fun, huh, Brother?
Sure is.
It's been a long time since
we've been out sightseeing like this.
Sightseeing?
That's rich!
Here, take this.
A knife?
This is an uninhabited island, after all.
No electricity, no wells, no houses to shelter you from the rain,
and no wild animals... at least, probably not.
For one month, you two are to
survive by yourselves on this island.
Oh, and during that time,
the use of alchemy is prohibited.
What is this?!
I'll come to pick you up
in one month.
J-Just a sec!
One is all, all is one.
If you don't find
the answer in one month,
I'm sending you
back to Resembool.
See ya!
One is all, all is one.
We understand it now,
but at the time...
Yeah.
We didn't have a clue
what she was saying—not at the time.
One is all, all is one.
Good grief, that auntie has given us homework that doesn't make sense.
What could it mean?
Is it a riddle?
I don't get it at all.
But unless we give her an answer in a month,
we won't get any real training.
Aw, jeez!
How is this supposed to be alchemy training?!
That auntie tricked us!
Let's go to sleep.
How about we get up early tomorrow and find some food?
Mm-hmm.
Al? You going to the bathroom?
What is it, Brother?
You can use the bathroom by yourself...
You idiot! Open your eyes!
Get out!
You've gotta be kidding!
If we run, then our training will be—
Brother!
Damn!
Al!
Damn...
Run!
Okay!
Now what?
Don't get lost on me, Al...
I don't taste good!
Brother, it's me!
Al! Thank goodness!
I thought I'd lost you!
It's a fox.
Ah, there's two of them.
How'd it go?
We've got dinner!
Make sure to dry off,
or else you'll rust.
Right.
Who was that man?!
I'm scared! I'm scared to death!
And she said there were no wild animals here!
There's something even worse than wild animals here!
What should we do?
What can we do?
It's another month before they're coming for us.
For the time being, we can't fight on empty stomachs.
You did it!
We've got food!
We can catch it with
the right kind of trap!
So...
How do we eat it?
We stick it!
We stick it?
You'll have to do it.
No! Brother, you do it!
I've never killed an animal before.
Neither have I!
That's not fair! You always force me to do the things you don't want to!
I what?!
Hold it!
You're not getting away from us!
Brother!
Are you okay?
You're hurt pretty bad!
That damned fox!
Where'd he go? That bastard!
Brother!
It has children.
I wonder if she's their mother.
Mm-hmm.
Let's give up on meat
and go for fish...
I wonder if you can eat fox...
Take it easy.
Got one!
Fire!
Food!
We humbly partake!
All right!
Brother...
What's the matter?
Yow!
Just come with me.
Ow-ow-ow!
What is this?
Don't give me "what is this?"
Don't dig right in just
because you're hungry!
It wasn't me.
But...
Your handprint is right here.
Take a close look.
This is a right hand.
Sure enough, someone's here.
Here? You don't mean...
It's possible that Sensei brought them here for the same reason.
Brother, where are you going?
Let's go check around. We'll find something to eat while we're at it, too.
There's no way we're giving up!
Twenty-eight more days!
Say...
What did we come here for, again?
Beats me...
What would happen
if we died here?
No way...
Winry and Grandma
would grieve for us.
There's still a lot of
things I want to do.
All of this... What does it
have to do with alchemy?!
I've had enough!
I want to go home!
Where is he?
This guy...
I found some food for Brother.
Brother!
Come look!
Brother? I wonder what's the matter...
You called, Al?
Brother!
Then who was that just now?
Why, you!
A cicada?
I get it...
It's dead...
Death...
When you die,
this is what happens...
Let go of Al...
Let go of Al!
We talked about what would happen if we died here, remember?
Mm-hmm. Everyone would grieve.
Um, that's the subjective part.
Looking at it objectively,
if I died, the world would keep on going
as if nothing had happened.
Your existence is a tiny one.
Don't call me small!
Ee-yow!
Well, if I, with my small existence,
were to die, my body would still remain.
Water, carbon, ammonia, lime,
phosphorous, saltpeter, salt, sulfur, magnesium, fluorine, manganese, and aluminum, right?
Right.
That and a handful of other elemental compounds are all that I am, right?
My body, I mean.
After all, I'm fated to be
broken down by bacteria
and become nourishment for plants.
But then those plants will raise grazing animals...
And the grazing animals will feed carnivorous animals...
Without even being aware of it, we naturally go on circulating.
I'm sorry about this.
There's a giant flow that
we can't see with our eyes.
Whether you call it the universe, or the world, I don't know,
but, Al, you and I are one little part within the larger flow.
One within all.
However, all of the ones have to
come together for the all to exist.
The world follows the flow of
greater laws that we can't even imagine.
We learn that flow,
break it down, and reconstruct it.
And that's alchemy.
Thirty days!
We've got breakfast!
It is the appointed day.
One is all, all is one.
Let's hear your answer.
"All" is the world!
"One" is me!
Very well.
We'll move on to real training.
All right!
I guess that guy isn't here after all.
That's okay, isn't it?
We more or less got what Sensei was trying to tell us.
Mm-hmm.
Back then,
we arrived at the answer.
But still, that alone wasn't enough.
The truth is, back then,
we should have realized that
transmuting Mom was a mistake.
It could be that everything
we're about to do is, as well.
I'm sure Sensei would agree.
Have you remembered?
Yes.
Do you realize it?
Um, Sensei, what you're trying to tell us is...
It's true that we did try to transmute our mom.
The way we are now
is the outcome of that.
However, that is precisely why
we want to get everything back.
You intend to get back through error that which you lost through error?
Maybe it is wrong of us...
But...
if that's the case,
what are we supposed to do?
We're going to move forward.
We are...
still alive, after all.
And that's enough?
Yes!
In that case...
Is someone there?
What are you talking about?
Hasn't someone been living on this island since long ago?
You think it could be that
masked man from before?
That couldn't be.
The reason being, that was me.
Wh-What do you mean?!
Just in case, I had him keep watch, since I couldn't let you die on me.
S-So then...!
Apparently, that doesn't
seem to be the case here.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 29: "The Untainted Child"
Brother, I saw it—
the old scar on his shoulder.